A Place to Return to
(いの)いっ…。
Oww!
Try to bear with it.
(サクラ)我慢して。
これで 少し楽になるはず。
This should ease the pain a bit.
Thank you, Sakura...
(いの)サンキュー サクラ。
《サクラ : 傷が深い…
ここでは応急処置だけね》
The wound is deep.
I'll do what I can here...
(ナルト)サクラちゃん。
Sakura...
How is Yuukimaru doing?
幽鬼丸の様子は？
今 シズネ先輩たちが診てるわ。
Shizune Senpai and the others
are tending to him now.
(ヒナタ)ひどい… 経絡系が…。
This is terrible. His Chakra Network is...
(シズネ)ええ
かなりのダメージを受けているわ。
Yes, he's suffered a lot of damage...
(シズネ)たとえ治療をしても 完全に
元に戻すことは不可能でしょう。
Even with treatment,
it'd be impossible to restore him
to normal completely.
三尾をコントロールする能力は
幽鬼丸の体に➡
It seems the power to control
the Three-Tails took quite a toll
かなりの負担を
強いるものだったようです。
on Yuukimaru's body.
(カカシ)命を削る術だったと？
The Jutsu reduced his life...?
はい。 精密な検査をするまでは
断定できませんが➡
Yes.
I can't be certain until we conduct
a thorough examination,
おそらく もう幽鬼丸に
以前の力は残っていないでしょう。
but it's likely that Yuukimaru no longer
has the powers he once had.
(ヤマト)これで 三尾を操る術は
失われてしまいましたね。
We've now lost our only chance
of controlling the Three-Tails...
(カカシ)この子にとっては それで
よかったのかもしれないな。
Perhaps, for this child,
it's better that way...
シズネのねえちゃん。 幽鬼丸は？
Shizune, how is Yuukimaru?
命に別状はないわ。
まだ眠ってるけど…。
He'll live. He's still asleep...
よかったわね 助かって。
Thank goodness he made it.
ああ…。
Yeah...
だけど オレ 結局 コイツに何も
してやれなかった。
えっ。
But...
I wasn't able to help him
at all in the end...
What?
思っているヤツがいるところが
帰る場所って➡
I foolishly told him "wherever someone
thinks about you is the place to return to..."
そう偉そうに教えたのによ。
コイツは やっと見つけた帰る場所を
目の前で なくしちまったんだ。
But right before his eyes,
he lost that very place to return to.
That wasn't your fault.
そんなの アンタのせいじゃない。
けどよ…。
But still...
((幽鬼丸 : やっぱり
紅蓮さんのいるところが➡
You are the one I should return to,
after all...
ボクの帰るべき場所だもん。
And I'm the one
you should return to, Guren.
紅蓮さんも ボクのいるところに
帰ってくればいいんだよ。
(紅蓮)ああ… 誓う。
I promise you...
I will never leave your side.
もう お前のそばから
離れることはない。
I will always think of you.
お前のことを ずっと思い続ける。
うん。 ボクは ず～っと
紅蓮さんのことを➡
Uh-huh...
And I will always think of you, Guren.
思い続けているよ。
(これからも ず～っと))
From now, and forever...
うっ…。
ナルト…。
Naruto...
ごめんな 幽鬼丸。
I'm sorry. Yuukimaru...
(カツユ)状況は以上です。 綱手様。
And that is the situation, Lady Tsunade.
(綱手)そうか… わかった。
I see... I understand.
(綱手)カツユ みんなに
帰還命令を伝えろ。
Katsuyu, order everyone to return.
あっ… よろしいのですか？
Are you sure?
We have no choice.
(綱手)仕方あるまい。
It would be impossible to
have them continue their mission.
このまま任務を続行させるのは
不可能だろう。
その子供が能力を失った以上➡
Now that the child has lost his powers,
大蛇丸は もはや尾獣には
手は出せないはず。
Orochimaru can no longer
do anything to the Tailed Beast.
こちらも一度 引きあげ
体勢を整えたうえで➡
We'll pull back for now, regroup,
and come up with a new plan.
再度 作戦を立て直す。
But Orochimaru is not the only one
who is after the Three-Tails...
(カツユ)しかし 三尾を狙う者は
大蛇丸だけでは…。
そんなことは 百も承知だ。
I'm perfectly aware of that.
But the Three-Tails is an adversary
that has given us
だが三尾は 我々を
ここまで手こずらせた相手。
a great deal of trouble up to this point.
暁とて たやすくは…。
Even the Akatsuki won't
have an easy time.
すぐに交代の忍を向かわせる。
I'll send Ninja to
replace them immediately.
その者たちが到着次第
全員 撤収しろと伝えろ！
Once they arrive,
have them tell everyone to withdraw!
はい！
Right away.
綱手様のお言葉は 以上です。
Those are Lady Tsunade's orders.
わかりました。
さっそく 皆に伝えます。
Understood.
We'll inform everyone immediately.
We have new orders from Lady Hokage.
(カカシ)火影様より新たな指示だ。
我々は 現在の任務を中断。
We will abort our current mission.
すぐに
里に戻るように とのことだ。
Our orders are to return to
the village immediately.
(みんな)えっ!?
(サイ)急な話ですね。
- What?
- Huh?!
That was sudden.
Hey c'mon, is it okay to leave
the Three-Tails?
(キバ)おいおい！
三尾をほっといてもいいのかよ！
それなら心配はない。
We won't have to worry about that.
ボクたちの代わりに
監視にあたる忍が➡
They're sending Ninja to replace us
and maintain the watch.
到着することになっている。
だけど…。
But still...!
There's nothing we can do
even if we remain here.
ここに残っても 今の私たちに
打てる手はないわ。
みんな あまりに傷つきすぎた。
Everyone has suffered too many wounds.
それよりは
今回得た情報を持ち帰り➡
Lady Tsunade has decided that
it would be more effective
if we brought back the information
we've gained this time around
次の作戦に
役立てることこそ重要だと➡
綱手様は 判断されたのよ。
and apply it to our next plan instead.
出発は 明朝だ。
We'll move out tomorrow morning.
I want you all to get a good night's rest
before we move out.
各自 移動に備え
今夜は しっかりと➡
休んでおくように。
うっ… うぅ うっ…。
(牛頭)紅蓮さん…。
Guren...
紅蓮さん…。
牛頭 なぜ…。
Gozu?
Why're you...
なぜ お前は私を助ける？
Why're you saving me...?
覚えてますか？
あの日のことを。
Do you remember...that day?
I was placed in solitary after losing control
during Orochimaru's experiment...
大蛇丸の実験後 大暴れして
独房に入れられたオレは➡
食事はおろか
水もろくに与えてもらえず➡
I was hardly given any water
or food to speak of.
渇き果て 死にかけていた。
I was on the verge of dying from thirst.
そこへ あなたが➡
Then you came and kindly gave me
a ladleful of water.
杓にひとすくいの水を
恵んでくだすった。
それで オレは
死なずにすんだのです。
Because of that, I was able to survive.
その日以来 オレは…。
Ever since that day, I...
フン 忘れたよ
きっと気まぐれだ。
I don't even remember.
I must've been feeling generous.
たとえ そうだとしても➡
Even if that were so,
I've always admired you since then...
ずっと
お慕い申し上げております。
はっ！
紅蓮さん…。
Guren...
イテッ！ イタタ…。
O-Ow...
Huh?!
Yuukimaru?!
幽鬼丸？
Damn!
クソッ！
先輩。
Senpai.
ハァ ハァ… ハァ ハァ…。
クソ！ どこ
行っちまったんだってばよ。
Damn! Where could he have gone?!
アイツ まだ 体だって
まともじゃねえだろうに！
His body's...
in no condition to...!
ハァ ハァ ハァ… 幽鬼丸。
Yuukimaru...
ハァ ハァ…。
クソ！
Damn!
草笛…
もしかして 幽鬼丸なのか？
A grass whistle?
Could it be Yuukimaru?!
戻ってこい 幽鬼丸！
Come back! Yuukimaru--!
幽鬼丸！
Yuukimaru!
Where are you, Yuukimaru?!
どこだ？ 幽鬼丸！
Damn! It's my fault...!
クソ！ オレのせいで。
幽鬼丸…。
Yuukimaru...
これは…。
This is...!
Why would he leave behind something
as important as...?
何だって アイツ
こんな大事なもの…。
ヒビひとつ入ってない…。
There isn't even a single crack...
《そうか そういうことか》
I see. So that's it...
(キバ)幽鬼丸が消えた？
Yuukimaru disappeared?
まさか あの状態で動けるなんて。
How could he even move
in his condition?
おい ナルト お前➡
Hey, Naruto.
You were in the room with him.
同じ部屋にいたのに
気づかなかったのかよ？
Didn't you notice?
No, I guess not.
まあな。
はあ？ なんだよ それ。
Huh?! How can you call yourself
a Ninja?!
忍が 聞いて呆れるぜ
さすが下忍！
Just what you'd expect from a Genin!
うっせえな
お前だって寝てたじゃねえかよ！
Shut up!
You were asleep, too, you know!
Why you...!
(キバ)んだと？ オレを スタミナオバケの
テメエと一緒にすんじゃねえ！
Don't put me in the same league
as a stamina freak like you!
(サクラ)アンタたちが もめたって
しかたないでしょ！
Arguing won't do any good!
でも 心配ね 幽鬼丸
行くあてなんかないんだろうし。
But I'm worried about Yuukimaru.
He has nowhere to go, and...
We can't just ignore him!
Let's all look for him!
(リー)放ってはおけません！
ここは みんなで捜しましょう！
I agree!
そうよね！
(シノ)その必要はない。
That won't be necessary.
なぜなら 三尾に関する力を
失った子どもは➡
The reason is...
because a child who lost his power
to control the Three-Tails
我々にとって
もはや脅威ではないからだ。
is no longer a threat to us.
そういう問題ではありません！
That's not the issue here!
いや シノの言うとおりだな。
No, Shino is right.
逃げ出した子どもを わざわざ
捜して出してやる義務はない。
We're under no obligation to look
for a child who ran away.
それに ボクたちには
帰還命令も出ていることだしね。
And besides,
we've been ordered to return.
そんな… いいんですか ナルト君？
But that's...!
Are you okay with that, Naruto?!
ああ 心配ねえ。
Yeah, there's nothing to worry about.
アイツなら 大丈夫だってばよ。
He can handle himself.
ナルト？
Naruto...?
そろそろ出発だな。
We'd better be on our way.
Sorry to keep you all waiting, Kakashi.
お待たせしました カカシさん。
(大蛇丸)うまく暁を
揺さぶれればと➡
I was hoping we could have
shaken up the Akatsuki...
思っていたんだけど。
I'm sorry. I didn't count on
the Leaf Ninja interfering.
(カブト)申し訳ありません
木ノ葉の邪魔が入るとは
計算外でした。
And so, did that woman...
それで あの女…
紅蓮は死んだの？
Guren die?
ええ 残念ながら。
Regretfully, yes.
なかなか
おもしろい能力の持ち主でしたが。
She possessed very interesting powers...
フフ 心にもないことを。
Like you mean that...
Maybe you were the one who killed her?
殺したのは
あなたなんじゃないの？
滅相もない。
まあ いいわ。
Heaven forbid.
Well, never mind.
あの程度の者なら
いくらでも替えがきく。
We can find any number of replacements
for someone of her ability.
ですが 幽鬼丸が…。
But Yuukimaru...
捨て置きなさい 今となっては…
ゴホッ！
Leave it.
At this point...
大蛇丸様！
今 薬をお持ちします！
Lord Orochimaru!
I'll bring your medicine right away!
ゲホッゲホッ!!
《もはや あの器も限界か》
That host body has reached its limit...
ハァ ハァ…。
フフフ 今となっては
すべてが無意味。
At this point, it has lost all meaning...
もうすぐ 彼の体が
手に入るのだから。
Because soon,
I will possess his  body...
どうしたの ナルト？
What's the matter, Naruto?
いや なんでもねえ。
No, it's nothing...
フフフ！
定時連絡か？
ああ。
Is that the regular report?
Yeah...
霧が出てきたな。
A fog is forming.
According to the unit we're taking over for,
引継ぎによると
時折 三尾が放出するものらしい。
it's apparently created by
the Three-Tails.
幻覚作用があるから
気をつけろよ。
It induces hallucinations, so be careful.
(デイダラ)ソイツは 初耳だな うん。
That's news to me, hmm...
お前 その装束！
You! That costume...
しまっ…。
Dam--!
フン！
(トビ)いや～ さすがデイダラ先輩！
Humph...
Oh wow! Deidara Senpai,
that was awesome!
見張りはこれで全部ですね。
That's the last of the lookouts.
Your info was way off.
お前の情報とは
だいぶ違うな うん。
確か 木ノ葉と別勢力が
三尾をめぐって➡
"A force separate from
the Leaf Ninja was engaged
in a vigorous clash over the Three-Tails."
派手にぶつかり合ってる。
じゃなかったか？
Wasn't that what you said?
ん～ そのはずなんですけどね。
おかしいなぁ。
Well, that's how it was supposed to be...
That's odd.
But oh well, it's good that we got rid
of the ones in our way.
まあ でもジャマなのがいなくなって
よかったじゃないですか。
今のうちのに とっととノルマ
こなしちゃいましょうよ。
Let's make our quota right now
while we have the chance!
You're a hundred years too young
to be giving me orders, hmm...
お前が オレに指図するのは
100年早い うん。
うん！
ちょ… ちょっと 先輩！ 幻覚の話
聞いてなかったんですか？
H-H-Hey, Senpai!
Weren't you listening to the story
about the hallucinations?
誰に言ってる？
オイラのアートをなめんなよ。
Who do you think you're speaking to?
Don't underestimate my art.
Sheesh, he's got a short temper...
はぁ。 ったく 短気なんだから
ま 三尾を探すったって
結構 広い湖だからな。
That's a huge lake to find
the Three-Tails in.
It'd be faster if it appeared on its own.
自分から
出てきてもらうのが早いだろう。
うん！
いや～ 改めて見るとホント
何か でかい亀みたいですね。
Oh! On closer inspection,
it looks something like a huge turtle.
A powerful one...
強そうですね。
So that's the Three-Tails...
これが三尾か。
やっぱ ここは➡
I think I'll leave it for you to handle,
Deidara Senpai.
デイダラ先輩にお任せします。
トビ！ お前晴れて
暁のメンバーになったんだろ。
Tobi, you formally became
a member of Akatsuki, right?
あとは お前がやれ うん。
You take care of the rest, hmm!
No way...
そんな…。
うわ～っ！
あ～っ！ 来た～っ！
It's coming!
水系のヤツなら
鬼鮫さんに任せたほうが➡
If it's a water creature,
shouldn't we have let Kisame handle it?!
よかったんじゃないんですか？
I'd say they assigned
the wrong person for the job!
人選ミスでしょ これ！ ギャーッ！
情けねえな。
Pitiful, I'd say.
喝！
Now!
ギャーッ！
どうかなさいましたか？
いや。
Is something the matter?
No...
皆さん 無事に火の国に
入られたようですね。
It appears everyone has entered
the Land of Fire safely.
そうか ご苦労。
I see. Good work.
ではカツユ お前は戻れ。
はい。
You may now return, Katsuyu.
Yes.
I did it! Banzai! Banzaai!
(トビ)やった～！
バンザ～イ！ バンザ～イ！
デイダラさん！ 見ました オレの術！
コイツ イチコロですよ～！
Deidara, did you see my Jutsu?!
Just one time, and bam!
暁のメンバーになって➡
You can understand why
I was given this important assignment
いきなり
こんな大役を任されるのも➡
right after formally becoming a member
of Akatsuki, can't you?!
頷けるってもんでしょ？
オレって やるもんでしょ？
いいや。 オイラの起爆粘土が
アートしただけだろ。
No... It was probably my clay bomb
doing its artistic work.
オイラの芸術のおかげだろうが！
うん。
You have my artistry to thank, hmm.
手を貸してやったのも忘れて➡
Don't get so carried away that
you forgot that I lent you a hand!
１人で盛り上がってんじゃ
ねえよ！
If you're a member of Akatsuki,
don't talk so much and act more cool.
暁のメンバーなら
もっと口数は少なく➡
もっとクールに振る舞え。
要するに➡
In other words, "cool = art"!
クール イコール アートだ！
いいか。 アートってのはな➡
Listen, art is a passionate moment
coming from cool emotions--!
クールな感情から
かもし出される➡
(デイダラ)情熱的な一瞬の…。
(トビ)先輩こそ口数が多いっすね。
Senpai, you talk a lot.
ハハハ ハハハ ハハハ…！
(トビ)ん… 冗談！
I was joking...!
(トビ)ギャーッ!!
どうした？
いや。
What is it?
It's just that...
contact from the unit that headed for
the lake is rather late, don't you think?
湖に向かった連中なんだが➡
連絡が遅くないか？
うん…。
念のため報告をあげておくか。
Let's file a report, just in case.
Listen, Tobi.
(デイダラ)いいかトビ。
図に乗ってんじゃねえぞ うん。
You shouldn't press your luck!
The Three-Tails was just weak
because it didn't have a Jinchuriki host.
三尾は人柱力じゃなかったぶん
弱かっただけだ。
力をコントロールする頭が
なかったからな。
It didn't have a mind to control its power.
はぁ… おいトビ！
Hey, Tobi.
You don't have to be so cool
as to stop talking altogether.
そこまでクールに
口数減らすことはねえよ。
At least answer me...
ちゃんと返事くらい…。
(トビ)ムニャ。
Hmm?!
あぁ～ ダメ ダメです。
そ そ そ そこは…。
Oh that's the spot...
あっ イ イヤ～ン…。
Oh my...
(デイダラ)テメエにゃ
ちょうどいい目覚ましだ！
This is the perfect wake up
for you, I'd say. You bastard!
この野郎!!
(キバ)ふぅ！ 久しぶりに
帰ってきた気がするなぁ！
Wow, it feels like I hadn't
been back in ages.
(シノ)任務につぐ
任務だったからな。
We had one mission after another...
Dinner tonight is at Ichiraku!
今日の晩メシは
一楽で決まりだぜ！
ねぇ ナルト！
Say, Naruto.
ん？
幽鬼丸のことだけど➡
Huh?
About Yuukimaru...
Are you sure it was best that way?
ホントに あれでよかったわけ？
You used to worry so much about him.
アンタ あんなに気にしてたのに。
いいんだ！
どうせ捜したって➡
That's okay.
Besides, even if we went looking for him,
he wouldn't be easy to find anyway.
簡単には
見つかんなかったろうし。
どういうこと？
やっぱさ➡
What do you mean?
The Pervy Sage's words
were true, after all.
エロ仙人の言葉は正しかったんだ。
He said wherever someone cares
about you is the place you return to.
思ってるヤツがいるところが
帰る場所なんだって。
思って思って思い続ければ➡
If you believe, and keep thinking,
about that person...
your feelings will surely get across, he said.
それは絶対
通じるんだってばよ！
えっ これって… まさか!?
What? Is this...what I think it is?
So...we should keep thinking, too.
だから オレらも思い続けようぜ。
サスケの帰る場所。
We need to create a place
that Sasuke can return to.
作っとかなきゃなんねえしな。
うん！
Right.
So that's your move...
Just as I expected.
You are weaker than me...
There's no longer any need for me
to give you my body.
You Uchiha fledgling...!
If I hadn't been a fledgling,
you'd have had no chance at me, right?
Silence!
I don't like the way you do things.
You continue to toy with others
for your own pathetic reasons...